PETER KIMELI TANUI

DevSecOps Engineer

Address Nairobi, Kenya, 0100

WWW https://kimpetertanui.github.io

Phone 254-708-995320

E-mail kimelipeter20@gmail.com

Talented DevSecOps Engineer/Senior Software Developer with 6 years of enterprise in software and mobile development and a broad range of industries including News Media, Mobile Payments, B2B, Restaurant Management, Integrated Commerce and Banking. Solid understanding of full mobile and Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including Waterfall and Agile methodologies. Well conversant with version control including CVS, SVN, GitLab and Git. Android experience and Expertise. Dedicated to continuously developing, implementing, and adopting new technologies to maximize development efficiency and produce innovative applications. Messaging frameworks. RabbitMQ,Apache Kafka, monitoring tool: Prometheus; DevOps tools: Jenkins, GitLab CI/CD, Docker,Kubernetes

Work History

2021-08 - Current

DevSecOps Engineer

Safaricom PLC, Nairobi, Nairobi

- Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment
- Built and deployed Docker containers to break up monolithic app into microservices, improving developer workflow, increasing scalability, and optimizing speed
- Automate build and deployment using Jenkins to reduce human error and speed up production processes
- Elp scale our platform for better customer experience
- Improve deployment process within AWS
- Improve automated test and simulation frameworks in the pipeline
- Develop and automate standard operating procedures around common failure scenarios
- Monitor, analyze, and report performance statistics for cloud hosted environments
- Develop application performance management to measure and act upon performance data
- Write clean, well-documented, and resilient code.
- Partner with our IT Team to provide support, maintenance, plan for future growth and development, and manage the SharePoint environment
- Regularly create and update the reports on status of agreed performance indicators to the Coordinator / Team Leader / Department Head
- Design and develop SharePoint master pages and create new SharePoint web content
- Provide strategies for continuous improvements through best-practices and standards
- Create/Deploy/Update Workflows (SPD, VS, Java, C#, etc.)

- Review SDLC of proposed solution with Manager before development commences
- Provide repeated, deadline-driven assistance to HR Team for employee and benefits related sections on VIC

2020-06 - 2021-08 Senior Software Engineer

Adalabs, Nairobi, Kenya

- Worked individually as well as part of a larger team on developing and maintaining multiple client applications
- Contributed to full life cycle development of eCOBba App
- Extensive use and implementation of Google Places API (JSON), PayPal Auth 2.0,
- Worked on multiple emulators to thoroughly develop and test deployment and interoperability on multiple platforms
- Documented architecture and implementation for internal and external consumption
- Implemented support for applications using Flickr API, Google Maps API, Facebook API, and Twitter AP
- Docker, Vagrant
- Git and GitLab
- Hell, Python scripting
- Working knowledge of data frameworks: Hadoop architecture and its ecosystem, Apache Spark,
- Apache Flume, Apache sqoop, Apache pig, Hive, data warehousing;
- Messaging frameworks. RabbitMQ, Apache Kafka and Apache Pusar, monitoring tool: Prometheus;
- DevOps tools: Jenkins, GitLab CI/CD, Docker
- Installed and configured software applications and tested solutions for functionality
- Checked client code for bugs and weaknesses using approved troubleshooting methods
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations
- Delivered unit-tested systems with required characteristics and within customerprescribed timeframes

2019-03 - 2020-05 **Senior Android Developer**

Mobitechtechnologies, Nairobi, Kenya

- Implemented features for various applications in Java, Kotlin, and C++
- Determined architectural and product design details for open-ended tasks or specifications
- Collaborated with quality engineers, user research, product management, design, and support teams to ensure quality in all phases of app development
- Worked closely with core technology teams and other platform teams to balance crossplatform consistency with Android-optimization
- Wrote elegant, self-documenting code, easy to read and adapt for other developers
- Reviewed design specs and engineering docs and provide feedback
- Key achievements:

- Created and tested 25+ Android apps and games that brought in about \$300K within a 6month period
- Integrated third party libraries including Picasso and ActionBarSherlock
- Implemented Clean Architecture using Dagger2 and RxJava
- Used specific code versioning tools to manage and implement changes to programs.

2018-01 - 2019-02

Senior Software Engineer

EldoHub Innovation, Nairobi, Kenya

- Adopted engineering best practices and delivered highest quality scalable solutions
- Paired with fellow engineers to brainstorm ideas, debug problems and review code
- Designed and implemented scalable application programming interfaces
- Delivered documentation for design decisions, estimating assumptions, code modules and performance metrics
- Understood full technology stack and underlying applications, services and databases, resulting in optimal program performance
- Worked with customers to define requirements and troubleshoot issues and architected and implemented new engineering applications to meet needs
- Created and maintained service desk diagnostics and job aids and reviewed with technicians to confirm clarit
- Developed complex software and systems deploying one or more programming languages
- Followed and supported change management practices and internal controls standards
- Developed e-commerce website to reduce cart abandonment rate by40%, resulting in increased online sales after go-live date
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design
- Boosted web traffic by improving navigation and rectifying bottlenecks
- Spearheaded production of page content such as visuals and text copy to meet project specifications
- Owned more than 5 projects per year from initial research and conceptual design through testing and implementation phases
- Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets
- Crafted SEO strategy and intuitive interface for site to achieve prominent rankings across top browser platforms
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface
- Built user interface, data visualizations and designed overall user experience, resulting in 40% increase in sales.

Education

2015-01 - 2019-01

Bachelor's degree: Computer Science

DEDAN KIMATHI UNIVERSITY oF TECHNOLOGY - Kenya

Certifications

Agile Foundations - LinkedIn

DevOps with AWS - LinkedIn

Scrum: The Basics - LinkedIn

Stay Lean with Kanban - LinkedIn

Design Thinking: Understanding the Process (2016) - LinkedIn

Learning AWS CloudFormation - LinkedIn

Terraform Certified

Referees

1. Engingeer Nixon Kipkorir

- Android Developer -
- Phone Number: 0702739804
- Email:nixwinner@gmail.com

2 .Prof Stanley Njoroge

- Fullstack Engineer-Adanian Labs Africa
- Phone Number :0705822035
- Email:Stanley.Njoroge@adanianlabs.io

3.Dr Susan Kwamboka

- Data Engineer -Safaricom PLC
- Phone Number: 0705137818
- Email:susankwamboka81@gmail.com

Skills

Agile

HTML and XML

Engineering standards

Database programming

Database management software

Web-based software engineering

API design knowledge

Build releases

Programming

Code reviews

Testing and maintenance

Solutions deployment